# **MD KAMRUZZAMAN**

Luxmipur, Gopalpur, Tangail, Bangladesh.

Mobile: +8801913031049 Email: kamrul4188@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kamrul4188



# **CAREER SUMMARY**

Experienced in electrical, electronics and instrumentation engineering include planning and undertaking of scheduled maintenance and responding to breakdown. Creating maintenance procedures, managing engineering and technical staff. Capability to work under pressure and gain a high level of problem-solving skills.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **National University of Singapore (NUS)**

Jan 2013 – Jun 2020

- Bachelor of Technology in Electronics Engineering, Honours
- Cumulative Average Point (CAP): 3.10/5.00
- Relevant modules completed includes Real-Time Embedded Systems, Programming for Computer Interface, Feedback Control System, Radiofrequency (RF) Communication, Signal & Systems, Device & Circuits, Computer Networking.

# **Singapore Polytechnic (SP)**

**Apr 2011 – Mar 2012** 

- Advanced Diploma in Process Control & Instrumentation
- Cumulative Grade Point Average (CGPA): 3.514/4.00
- Relevant modules completed include Automation & Programmable Controller Application, Intelligent Instrumentation & Measurement Systems. Process Control Engineering, Power System Planning and Control.

#### Mymensingh Polytechnic Institute, Bangladesh.

**Dec 2003 – Sep 2007** 

- Diploma in Electrical Engineering.
- Cumulative Grade Point Average (CGPA): 3.63/4.00
- Relevant modules completed include Electrical Engineering, Power System, AC Machine, Switchgear & Protections, Generation of Electrical Energy.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Service Engineer, DES Marine Singapore.

**Jun 2018 – May 2020** 

- Extended support, operationalized and troubleshooting of Heat Ventilation and Air-Conditioning (HVAC) system.
- Implemented maintenance strategies, procedures and led to routine maintenance, consulted technical support in fault diagnosis and repair.
- Assembling, installation and commissioning of an HVAC system such as ductwork, chiller and Air Handling Unit (AHU) on vessel.
- Interacted with client representative, vessel owners for analysed standard procedure, scheduling and assign manpower.
- Managed to deliver project duct installation of HVAC system on vessel 'Heerema Sleipnir' at SembCorp's Marine Tuas Boulevard Yard on time.

# Electronics Service Engineer, Ehsan Marine Pte Ltd, Singapore. Nov 2016 – Nov 2017

- Collaborated daily task with Project Manager and Production Engineer for construction project, adopted execution plan and monitoring progress.
- Supervised of calibration and service of various instrument at calibration lab, compiled a technical report and produce a certificate for calibrated equipment.
- Conducted calibration, repair and servicing of various electrical and pneumatic instruments on cargo ship.
- Evaluated various instruments include Oil Discharge Monitoring Equipment, bilge alarm system, temperature and pressure controllers.
- Response to customer inquiries and provided technical advice.

# Electrician, Keppel FELS Ltd, Singapore

Dec 2008 – Oct 2016

- Organized preventive maintenance schedule for plant machinery and equipment.
- Spearheaded maintenance process to ensure high efficiency of maintenance work.
- Assessed automation system, CNC operated plate and pipe cutting machines, overhead and gantry crane.
- Performed corrective maintenance to ensure machinery and equipment were refined within short period of time.
- Identified root cause of defect or breakdown, resolved and constructed cost-effective improvements work to prevent a recurrence.
- Supervised for electrical facility support of new shipbuilding project.

# Jr Engineer, Navana CNG Ltd, Bangladesh

Feb 2008 – Dec 2008

- Superintend of installation and commissioning of the electrical control system of Safe.s.r.l CNG refilling station.
- Coordinate with customer and scheduling, manpower and equipment of installation work
- Attended service calls for commissioned machine and provided technical support to the customer as per requirement.
- Support operation manager on the daily operation by providing service forms, reports, logs and breakdowns record.

# **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

# Director, NUS Electrical and Computer Engineering Club Executive, NUS Electrical and Computer Engineering Club Sep

Sep 2017 – Aug 2018 Sep 2016 – Aug 2017

- Strategized and interacted with organizing committees of various workshops, industrial visits and freshmen orientation programmes.
- Facilitated smooth event flow of all workshops to aid participant in learn through socializing.
- Advertised of club activity over various social media platform to obtain sponsorship and created positive value for organization.

### **Director, NUS ECE Freshmen Orientation Camp**

Jan 2017 – Jul 2018

• Arranged overall programme and conducted operation of camp to aid in bonding of freshmen and adjusting to school's environment and academic system.

- Providing guidance to new students for having fun and active socializing.
- Coordinated with organization committee while working closely with treasurer, secretary, logistic manager for planning, preparing and executing all orientation events.

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Using Python for Research from Harvard on edx in June 2020.
- Google IT Support Specialization from Google on Coursera in Sep 2018.
- CCNA Routing & Switching from American International University of Bangladesh (AIUB) in March 2008.
- Introduction to HMI/PLC integration from Institute of Technical Education (ITE), Singapore in Nov 2012.
- S7-300 Programming Basic from Siemens Singapore in Nov 2012.
- Autodesk AutoCAD-2012 Essentials from NTUC Learning Hub, Singapore in Sep 2012
- Implement PLC in Control System from Singapore Polytechnic in Oct 2012.
- Skill Evaluation Test One in Marine Electrical Technology from Institute of Technical Education (ITE), Singapore in Sep 2011.
- Shipyard Supervisors Safety Course from NTUC Learning Hub, Singapore in Dec 2010.
- Computer Repair & Maintenance form Institute of Technical Education (ITE) in May 2010

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Fluent in English and Bangla (both spoken and written).
- Proficient in Microsoft Office, Python, C and basic knowledge of C++.
- Skilled in PLC programming on Siemens LOGO.
- Expected Salary: Negotiable.

# REFERENCE

# • Shuvasish Bhowmick Country Director

ATEC\* Biodigesters International Email: engr.shuvasish@gmail.com

Mobile: +8801977655430